Office of the University President - Record Group 3 WLU.RG.0003
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Office of the University President - Record Group 3
Date Not Yet Determined
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Washington and Lee University. Office of the President
WLU.RG.0003
x Linear Feet
Scope and Contents
This record group contains materials created by the University's Presidents while carrying out their job duties.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is generally open for research use. Some materials may be restricted.
College presidents
- President John Delane Wilson
  - Memos to Board of Trustees, 1947-1994 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting Material, 1983-1989 (Box 2)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting Material, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
  - Board of Trustees Material, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Also contains Self Study Report and Long Range Plan
  - Alumni Correspondence U - Z, 1983-1991 (Box 6)
  - Alumni Correspondence, 1983-1991 (Box 5)
  - Alumni Correspondence on Coeducation, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Alumni Correspondence A - T, 1992-1994 (Box 8)
  - Alumni Correspondence S - Z, 1992-1995 (Box 9)
  - Coeducation, 1972-1984 (Box 10)
  - Coeducation, 1972-1984 (Box 11 (Pt.2))
  - Coeducation Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    Includes the Admissions Coeducation Study and alumni survey data.
    - Survey of Alumni Attitudes Towards Coeduction Research Report, 1984-05-18; 3 Item
      This survey of the alumni was conducted by the Southeastern Association of Research.
      Coeducation
  - President's Office Correspondence, 1960-1998 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985-1991 (Box 14)
    Includes departments and programs on campus. Also athletics and capital projects.
  - Miscellaneous, 1990-1995 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Faculty Tenure (Box 18)
  - Law School Correspondence, 1984-1992 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1995 (Box 20)
  - Dean Search - Law School, 1994 (Box 21 (Pt.1))
  - Dean Search - Law School, 1994 (Box 22 (Pt.2))
  - Dean Searches, 1986-1995 (Box 23)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1975-1993 (Box 24 (Pt.1))
  - Honorary Degrees, 1965-1975 (Box 25 (Pt.2))
  - Legal Files - Confidential (Box 26 (Pt.1))
  - Legal Files - Confidential (Box 27 (Pt.2))
  - Miscellaneous (Assistant to the President), 1977-1987 (Box 28)
  - Law School Evaluations, 1981-1994 (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1961-1983 (Box 30 (Pt.1A))
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1983-1991 (Box 31 (Pt.1B))
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1960-1988 (Box 32 (Pt.2A))
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1979-1987 (Box 33 (Pt.2B))
  - Miscellaneous, 1991-1992 (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987-1993 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 36)
  - Law Dean Search, 1994 (Box 37)
  - Speeches, 1983-1994 (Box 38)
  - Presidential Search Committee Files, Restricted, 1994
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted files - requires permission of the W&L president.
- President John William Elrod
  - Installment 1
    - Correspondence, 1992-1998 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
    - Advisory Committee, 1994-1999 (Box 3)
    - Law Dean Search, 1999 (Box 4)
      Restricted, requires permission of W&L president.
    - Miscellaneous Files & Trustee Files, 1971-1997 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1961-1993 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
      Includes information on the Reeves Center/Watson Addition,Science Center.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
      Includes Lee Chapel Renovation Project and Watson Gallery planning.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
      Includes materials about Lee Chapel
    - Budget (Box 11)
    - Trustee Files, Alumni Correspondence G-Z,Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Trip Files for John W. Elrod, James Farrar, SAE House Corp. Files, 1997-2000 (Box 13)
    - Trustee Files, Alumni Correspondence A - F (Box 14)
    - Budget & Miscellaneous, 1999-2001 (Box 15)
    - Trip Files for John W. Elrod, James Farrar, SAE House Corp. Files, 1994-2000 (Box 16)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Miscellaneous (Box 17 (Pt.1))
    - Farris Hotchkiss Miscellaneous (Box 18 (Pt.2))
    - Farris Hotchkiss Board of Trustees Meeting, 1994-1997 (Box 19)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Strategic Planning Files, Interview Files, 1997-1999 (Box 20 (Pt.1))
    - Farris Hotchkiss Strategic Planning Files, Interview Files, 1997-1999 (Box 21 (Pt.2))
    - Farris Hotchkiss Contact Reports A-Z (Box 22)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Chronological Files, 1993-1994 (Box 23)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Chronological Files, 1994 (Box 24)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Chronological Files, 1994-1995 (Box 25)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Chronological Files, 1995-1996 (Box 26)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Chronological Files, 1996-1997 (Box 27)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Chronological Files, 1997-1998 (Box 28)
    - Dean of the Law School, Miscellaneous Correspondence A (Box 29)
    - Dean of Students Miscellaneous Correspondence F (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence L-R (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 32)
    - Videocassette - Elrod Named President, Lee Chapel Ceremony,Inauguration, 1995 (Box 33)
    - Presidential Search Committee Files, 1995 (Box 34)
      Restricted. Requires permission of W&L president.
    - Miscellaneous, 1997-1998 (Box 35)
      Includes strategic planning information.
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1996 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1995 (Box 37)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Chronological Files, 1995 (Box 38)
    - Farris Hotchkiss Chronological Files, 1998 (Box 39)
  - Installment 2
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Given by the President's Office July 2005
    - President's Office Archived Files A, 1992-1998 (Box 1)
    - President's Office Archived Files A-C, 1959-1998 (Box 2)
    - President's Office Archived Files C, 1950-1998 (Box 3)
    - President's Office Archived Files, 1981-2005 (Box 4)
    - President's Office Archived Files D-F, 1981-1998 (Box 5)
    - President's Office Archived Files F-H, 1957-1998 (Box 6)
    - President's Office Archived Files H, 1981-1996 (Box 7)
    - President's Office Archived Files I-L, 1964-1998 (Box 8)
    - President's Office Archived Files L, 1950-1997 (Box 9)
    - President's Office Archived Files L-N, 1969-1998 (Box 10)
    - President's Office Archived Files N-P, 1962-1996 (Box 11)
    - President's Office Archived Boxes P-R, 1945-1996 (Box 12)
    - President's Office Archived Files R-S, 1979-1999 (Box 13)
    - President's Office Archived Files S, 1968-1999 (Box 14)
    - President's Office Archived Files S-T, 1949-1999 (Box 15)
    - President's Office Archived Files U-V, 1970-1999 (Box 16)
    - President's Office Archived Files (Box 17)
      U.S.News and World Report, President's Inauguration and Citation Letters.
    - President's Office Archived Files (Box 17A)
      Minority Issues, Miscellaneous Academy Rreprints
    - President's Office Archived Files (Box 17B)
      Financial Trends, Tuition Articles, Teaching Articles
- President Thomas Gerard Burish, 2002-2005
  - Installment 1
    This material was transferred from the President's Office on June 18, 2008.
    - President's Office Archived Files A-F (Box 1)
      This box contains materials on the following Corporafoundations,funds and trusts: Bonner,Carmaxx,Carpenter,Chicago Community,Christian A.Johnson Endeavor,Clarke Winchole,Commonwealth,DuPont,Dyson,EDFUND,Evans,Freuauff,Getty,Goodrich,Kenan,Kendal,Kerr,Knight,Liebman,Luce,Marshall,Mellon,Milhauser,Morris,Rawls,Pew,Reynolds,Stonewall Jackson,Telford,Watson,and Williams. Also pre-2005 Greek system, pre-2005 HR,pre-2005 Law School,five year plan, law class of 2007.
    - President's Office Archived Files F-J (Box 2)
      This box contains materials on the following corporafoundations,funds and trusts: Bonner,Carmaxx,Carpenter,Chicago Cummunity,Christian A.Johnson Endeavor,Clark Winchole,Commonwealth,DuPont,Dyson,EDFUND,Evans,Freuauff,Getty,Goodrich,Kenan,Kendal,Kerr,Knight,Liebman,Luce,Marshall,Mellon,Milhauser,Morris,Rawls,Pew,Reynolds,Stonewall Jackson,Telford,Watson,Williams. Also pre-2005 Greek system, pre-2005 HR, pre-2005 Law School, five year plan, class of 2007.
    - President's Office Archived Files J-V (Box 3)
      This box contains materials on the following coraporafoundations, funds and trusts: Bonner,Carmaxx,Carpenter,Chicago Community,Christian A. Johnson Endeavor,Clarke Winchole,Commonwealth,DuPont,Dyson,EDFUND,Evans,Freuauff,Getty,Goodrich,Kenan,Kendal,Kerr,Knight,Liebman,Luce,Marshall,Mellon,Milhauser,Morris,Rawls,Pew,Reynolds,Stonewall Jackson,Telford,Watson,Williams. Also pre-2005 Greek System, pre-2005 HR, pre-2005 Law School,five year plan, cClass of 2007.
  - Installment 2
    - President's Office Archived Files A-C (Box 1)
    - President's Office Archived Files C (Box 2)
      This box contains materials pertaining to Chavis through Commonwealth of Virginia-U.S. Senator George Allen.
    - President's Office Archived Files C-F (Box 3)
      This box contains materials pertaining to Communications and External Realtions though Facilities Management.
    - President's Office Archived Files F-L (Box 4)
      This box contains materials pertaining to Faculty Annual Fund through Line Printer related.
    - President's Office Archived Files M-S (Box 5)
      This box contains materials pertaining to Marks and Lundy through Sororities.
    - President's Office Archived Files S-U (Box 6)
      This box contains materials pertaining to Southern Association of Colleges and Schools through Unniversity Leadership Forum.
- William W. Pusey III
  - Memo on Faculty Appointments, Tenure, and Academic Freedom, 1967-09-20
- Miscellaneous
  - RG 4 Self-Study Reports, 1964-1999
    Includes Self-Study Handbook/Manual 1997-99 notebook.
  - African Americans at Washington and Lee website, 2013; Ruscio, Kenneth Patrick
    A timeline is being developed on the university website by a special working group established in August 2013 by Washington and Lee President Kenneth P. Ruscio to explore the role of African Americans in the history of the University. The University Library is capturing this timeline using Archive-It.
    Online Access
    View captures online at Washington and Lee University's Archive-It webpage
    Slavery; African Americans
  - Washington and Lee University Strategic Plan, 2018
    Washington and Lee University. Strategic Plans
  - Higher Education's Contribution to Democracy by Kenneth P. Ruscio. Opening Convocation., 2014-09-10
    Washington and Lee University. Opening Convocation.
  - Thank You! A Campaign for the Rising Generation at Washington and Lee University., 1998-2003
    Washington and Lee University. Campaigns
  - The Inauguration of William C. Dudley, 27th President of Washington and Lee, 2017-09-16
    Dudley, William C.